

Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

PROFILE

Gender: Male

Nationality: Iranian **Birth Date**: 6/30/1985

Software engineer with a strong background in design and development on Java platform. Keen learner and problem solver with a passion for algorithms, architecture, high throughput systems and Big Data. Highly experienced in developing financial and banking systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Science from Tehran Markazi Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2015 to Present.

Bachelor of Science from Qazvin Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2003 to September 2008.

CONTACT

Email: momeni.vesalian@gmail.com

Mobile: +98 912 020 6542

LinkedIn: Momeni Vesalian's profile Address: Flat 1, No. 5, Layeqi Alley, Qasr-od-Dasht St., Azarbayejan St.,

Tehran, Iran

WORK EXPERIENCE

Navaco (Maskan Bank)

Senior Java Developer

Mar 2017 - Present

I work as a member of CORE Banking architecture team to provide methodologies, middlewares and standards for the rest of the team to work with. I have a crucial role in designing architecture model, implementing several batch processing APIs and developing some important functionalities such as lending overnight calculation.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Senior Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2014 - Mar 2017

I worked as a member of Lending team to design and implement several infrastructural components related to lending system. I also designed and implemented conversion architecture model to migrate from old lending system to the new one. This involved writing 30000+ lines of Java and PL-SQL code.

Rayan Eghtesad Novin (Eghtesad Novin Bank)

Software Designer

May 2013 - Sep 2014

Rayan Eghtesad Novin company is one of the subsidiaries of Eghtesad Novin Bank. I worked as a member of Lending team which is one of the important CORE Banking modules. I designed repayment and settlement functionalities.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2009 - May 2013

I worked as a member of Lending team to design and implement several functionalities such as installment table calculation, product management, repayment and settlement. This also involved writing 150000+ lines of Java code.

IT and Communication Organization of Tehran Municipality

Java Developer

Oct 2008 - Sep 2009

TMICTO is one of Tehran Municipality affiliated organizations. It designs and implements all of the municipality software requirements. I worked on Media Observatory which crawled and extracted news from news websites.



Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

REFERENCES

Name: Ramin Farhanian

Position: Senior Software Engineer

Company: CDK Global

Email: ramin.farhanian@gmail.com

Mobile: +1 425 681 4507

Name: Hossein Pursultani

Position: Senior DevOps Engineer

Company: The University of Melbourne

Email: pursultani.hossein@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 402 626 041

Name: Abbas Sharifitabar
Position: Software Architect
Company: Hasin Technology

Email: abbas.sharifi@gmail.com

Mobile: +98 935 168 7200

Name: Hamid Banaian

Position: Chief Executive Officer

Company: Navaco

Email: h.banaeian@yahoo.com

Mobile: +98 912 579 3742

LANGUAGES

English

Persian

PROJECTS

Navaco CORE Banking

Sep 2017 - Present

Navaco CORE Banking project ordered by Maskan Bank to implement banks' functional and non-functional requirements such as accounting, deposit, lending, card and etc. Its serious implementation started around 2017 and I have been contributing to the project since March 2017 as a key member of architecture team. The team has a crucial role in the project and has some important tasks such as designing architecture model and implementing a framework that is used by other developers to reduce implementation time. In fact, I have a crucial role in designing architecture model and implementing several APIs for batch processing. I also design and implement some important banks' functional requirements such as lending overnight calculation.

Lotus CORE Banking

Feb 2008 - Present

Lotus project ordered by Parsian Bank to implement banks' functional and non-functional requirements such as accounting, deposit, lending, card and etc. Its serious implementation started around 2008. I have been contributing to the project since September 2009 as a key member of Lending team which deals with loans, bank guarantees and collateral. In fact, I had a crucial role in designing and implementing several functionalities such as installment table calculation, product management, repayment, settlement and modern banking services. I, besides, have cooperated in infrastructural components related to lending system. It is valuable to mention that Lotus project has been operational in all branches of Parsian Bank across the country since June 2015.

Lotus Lending Conversion

Mar 2011 - Dec 2015

Lending conversion project, which aimed to migrate all information from Negin CORE Banking Solution into Lotus CORE Banking Solution, started actively in March 2011. I was designated as the superior and architect in order to design and implement the project. Inherently critical constraints such as gradual data migration in several phases and live migration without disruption had to be done accurately, which made it difficult to implement the project. The conversion project composed of multi-threaded Spring Batch and PL-SQl routines. The project was utilized in three operational phases successfully without any faults.



Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

| OPERATING SYSTEM | Spring Spring |
|-----------------------------------|---------------------------|
| Linux | Spring Batch |
| Mac OS | Spring Security |
| Windows | Hibernate |
| | EclipseLink |
| IDE | iBatis |
| IntelliJ IDEA | JPA |
| Eclipse | Oracle PL/SQL Development |
| Visual Studio | Maven |
| RSA (Rational Software Architect) | Subversion |
| | Git |
| PROGRAMMING SKILLS | Log4j |
| Java | JUnit |
| Design Patterns | Test Driven Development |
| Software Architecture Patterns | Big Data Concepts |
| SOA | Hadoop |
| Big Data Architecture | Apache Spark |
| Distributed Systems | Apache Storm |
| Live Migration | UML |
| Concurrent Programming | Agile Methodologies |
| ЕЈВ | RUP Methodologies |
| JMS | CORE Banking Developer |
| <u>IATEX</u> | Lending System Developer |